roku.com 2015-09-09

# Privacy Policy | Roku Streaming Player

(Updated March 9th, 2015)

This Privacy Policy describes the information that Roku and its subsidiaries and affiliated companies (“Roku,” “we,” or “us”) collect about consumers through the Roku websites (“Roku Sites”), products utilizing Roku’s streaming platform, including the Roku players and Roku TVs, (collectively, “Roku Devices”), Roku Mobile Apps, or Roku’s accounts on third party social networking sites, and how we use and share that information. This Privacy Policy does not apply to websites, applications or services that display or link to different Roku privacy statements.

Roku’s services allow you to use and connect to third party services and third parties may collect information through the Roku Sites, Roku Devices, and Roku Mobile Apps. You may also connect with and follow Roku accounts on third party social networking sites. Roku’s Privacy Policy does not cover any third parties, their products, actions or services (except service providers acting solely on behalf of Roku). Roku cannot control how such third parties may collect, use or secure your data. For information about a third party’s privacy practices, please consult the privacy policy of that third party.

## Part I. Information Collection

### Information you provide

Information you provide Roku through the Roku Sites, Roku Devices or Roku Mobile Apps includes, for example, your name, email address, postal address, billing and shipping information, product purchase information, credit card and other payment data, product registration information, and demographics. If you connect with Roku’s accounts on third party social networking sites, we may also collect information about your social networking accounts, for example, your name, user name, or handle.

We also collect the personal information of other people, for example, if you provide email addresses of friends for referrals or postal addresses of recipients for gift purchases. We rely on you to obtain the permission of those other people to provide their personal information to us.

We may also combine information you provide with data we collect automatically (as further described below) and with data we receive from third parties.

### Information we collect automatically

#### Roku Site data

We may also automatically collect information related to the use of Roku Sites - for example, we collect your computer’s operating system type and version, Internet Protocol (IP) address, access times, browser type and language, and the websites you visited before coming to a Roku Site. We also use cookies to better understand your needs. A cookie is a small text file that our Web server places on your computer hard drive that includes a unique identifier. Cookies enable Roku and others to track usage patterns and deliver customized content, marketing messages and advertising to you. We also collect information using Web beacons. Web beacons are electronic images that may be used on Roku Sites or in our emails. We use Web beacons, for example, to deliver cookies, count visits, understand usage of the Roku Sites, Roku Devices and Roku’s services, analyze the effectiveness of Roku Site features and campaigns, and tell if an email has been opened and acted upon.

#### Roku Device data

We regularly and automatically collect information about your Roku Devices and your usage. The collected information about your Roku Devices includes, for example, the IP address associated with your Roku Devices, your device types and models, device identifiers, the retailer to whom your device was shipped, various quality measures, error logs, software version numbers, Wi-Fi network name (SSID – service set identifier) and strength. We also collect usage data such as your search history (including letters you key in for searches, and utterances provided in connection with your use of voice search), search results, content you select and view and content settings and preferences, channels you add and view, including time and duration in the channels, and other usage statistics. Usage information collected from Roku Devices may be associated with your Roku account or with product device identifiers (such as product serial numbers and other identifiers including those used for advertising and analytics). We associate device identifiers and usage data with your Roku accounts and other personally identifiable information for purposes described in this Policy.

#### Roku Mobile App data

If you download Roku Mobile Apps to a mobile device, we also automatically log information related to your mobile device and network. We may log, for example, your device type, device identifiers, Wi-Fi networking connection data, information about connected Wi-Fi devices, the types and versions of mobile operating system you use, time-stamped logs of data exchanges associated with the Roku Mobile Apps, and usage statistics associated with the Roku Mobile Apps such as your search history (including letters you key in for searches, and utterances provided in connection with your use of voice search), search results, content you select and view, and channels you add and view. We also log whether you use Play on Roku to play content stored on your mobile device (such as music, photos, or videos) through the Roku Device connected with the Roku Mobile App. To let you play content on your mobile device through the Roku Device, the Roku Mobile App needs permissions to access content and other information stored on your mobile device. 

#### Third party data collection

Third parties who provide us with analytics services for the Roku Sites, Roku Devices and Roku Mobile Apps may also automatically collect some of the information described above, including, for example, IP address, access times, browser type and language, device type, device identifiers and Wi-Fi information.

Other third parties, including channel providers, advertisers and ad networks, may also automatically collect information about you through the Roku Sites, Roku Devices, the Roku Mobile Apps or our services, including personally identifiable information about your online activities over time and across different websites, devices, online channels and applications when you use our services. For example, channel providers and advertisers can collect information about your Roku Devices (including unique identifiers) and your usage of their channels for their own purposes, including advertising and analytics. Some third parties, such as Google, may also collect information on behalf of Roku and others for online advertising purposes and to provide Roku and others statistics about users of the Roku Sites, Roku Devices or Roku Mobile Apps.

This Privacy Policy does not apply to the activities of these third parties when they are collecting or using data for their own purpose or on behalf of others. Please consult the respective privacy policies and statements of such third parties for more information, including [how Google uses data when you use its partner’s sites or apps](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/).

### Online advertising

#### Web advertising

We may use information collected using third party cookies and Web beacons on Roku Sites and in our emails to deliver Roku advertising displayed to you on third party sites. We also use cookie information to know when you return to Roku Sites after visiting these third party sites. We use this information and other information about you to try to understand your interests and show you relevant advertising and information about products and services offered by Roku and its partners.

Certain third party ad networks may automatically collect information about your visits to Roku Sites and other websites, such as your IP address, your Internet service provider, and the browser you use to visit Roku Sites (but not your name, address, email address or telephone number). They do this using cookies, Web beacons or other technologies. Information collected by such third parties may be used for analytics and advertising, including to deliver advertising relevant to your interests and to better understand the usage and visitation of Roku Sites and the other sites tracked by these third parties. This Privacy Policy does not apply to, and we are not responsible for, cookies or Web beacons and other technologies in third party advertising, and we encourage you to check the privacy policies of third party advertisers and/or ad services to learn about their use of cookies, Web beacons and other technology. You can learn more about their practices and your choices by visiting the [Digital Advertising Alliance in the USA](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/), [Digital Advertising Alliance in Canada](http://youradchoices.ca/) or the [Digital Advertising Alliance in Europe](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/) and visiting the privacy policies of the companies listed as customizing ads for your browser.

#### Roku Device and channel advertising

Each Roku Device has unique identifiers, including a unique, non-permanent identifier called Roku Identifiers for Advertisers (RIDAs). We use RIDAs and information associated with RIDAs to try to understand your interests, show you more relevant advertising from Roku or its channel providers or advertisers, and understand the effectiveness of such advertising. We supplement that information with information collected from Roku Sites, Roku Mobile Apps or third party data sources to further personalize the advertising you see on your Roku Devices. We use third party service providers, such as Google, to help deliver, personalize and target this advertising. 

Channel providers, third party advertisers and ad networks may also use RIDAs and other information they collect about you from your Roku Devices, for their own advertising purposes. They may use RIDAs to automatically collect information about your Roku Device, interactions with their channels and their advertising on your Roku Device. Information collected may be used, among other things, to deliver advertising relevant to your interests and to better understand the usage and visitation of their channels and the effectiveness of their advertising. This Privacy Policy does not apply to, and we are not responsible for, the data collection, data usage, advertising, and other activities of channel providers, third party advertisers and ad networks. If you would like more information about the data collection and usage practice of these third parties and your choices, please visit their respective privacy policies.

To understand your choices regarding use of RIDAs for personalized advertising, see “Roku Device and channel RIDA choices.”

## Part II.  Information Usage

Information collected by Roku is used by Roku and others on Roku’s behalf for the following purposes:

  * to understand how you and other users are using the Roku Devices, Roku Mobile Apps, Roku Sites and our other products and services in order to make them better;
  * to personalize your experience, offer you relevant content and recommendations, and display marketing and advertising tailored to your preferences;
  * to fulfill your orders and to provide customer support;
  * for marketing purposes, including sending you emails about products, events, promotions and offers from Roku or its partners or advertisers;
  * to send you service information, including confirmations, invoices, notices, updates, security alerts, and support and administrative messages;
  * to respond to your comments and questions and provide customer service;
  * for analyzing marketing and advertising effectiveness, our user base, product and service usage, feature popularity, software and hardware quality, and to improve and influence the design of future products and services;
  * to enforce our terms and conditions or protect our business or users; and
  * to protect, investigate, and deter against fraudulent, unauthorized, or illegal activity.

## Part III.  Information Sharing

### Your sharing

You can share your reviews publicly on the Roku Sites and can publicly share comments and content when you connect with Roku on Roku’s accounts on third party social networking sites. Please be mindful of your own privacy needs as you choose what to share and make public. We cannot control the privacy or security of information you choose to make public.

### Roku’s sharing

Roku may share personally identifying information with your consent, for example, when you agree to our sharing of your personally identifying information with other third parties for their own marketing purposes, subject to their separate privacy policies.

Roku may also share information with third parties whose services are integral to the use of the Roku Devices. For example, we may share information collected from the Roku Devices with content providers which have developed channels for the Roku Devices. The use of data by such content providers is subject to their respective privacy policies.

Roku uses third parties (including contractors and service providers) to help with its operations, which may require that they access and use your information. For example, Roku may use a third party to communicate with you (via telephone, email, or letter) about our products or services, to send information to you, to process and collect payment via your credit card (if applicable), to provide customer support, and to perform analytics and other work that we may need to outsource.

We may share some or all of your information with our current or future “affiliates” (which means a parent company, any subsidiaries, joint ventures, or other companies under a common control), in which case we will require our affiliates to honor this Privacy Policy.

Roku may also share your information with others in connection with or during negotiation of any merger, financing, acquisition, bankruptcy, dissolution, transaction or proceeding involving sale, transfer, divestiture or disclosure of all or a portion of our business or assets to another company.

Roku may also share your information to (i) comply with laws or to respond to lawful requests and legal process, (ii) to protect the rights and property of Roku, our agents, customers, and others, including to enforce our agreements, policies, and terms of use, or (iii) in an emergency to protect the personal safety of Roku, its customers, or any person.

Our services may allow you to share information with others, for example, our websites offer developer forums and message boards. Please be advised that information posted in these venues will be publicly available.

Finally, we may also share aggregated and/or anonymized information about you, including demographics data, with others for a variety of purposes, including for their own uses, for example, for improving their products and services for Roku and others. 

## Part IV.  Information Access and Choices

### General requests

If you wish to ask for access, correction, or deletion of any of your personal information held by us or a change in the way we use your information, please contact us at: [customer.advocate@roku.com](mailto:customer.advocate@roku.com). We will use commercially reasonable efforts to respond to your request in a timely manner. However, Roku may only provide access to, correction of, or deletion of, personal information as required by applicable law.

### Email marketing choices

Our marketing emails tell you how to “opt-out” of receiving further marketing emails. If you opt out, we may still send you non-marketing emails. Non-marketing emails include emails about your accounts and our business dealings with you, and requests that you participate in surveys.

### Roku Site tracking choices

When you visit Roku Sites, we and others give you the following choices about use of mechanisms for tracking, including tracking of your online activities over time and across different websites and online services by third parties. Many Web browsers are set to accept cookies by default. If you prefer, you can usually choose to set your browser to remove cookies and to reject cookies from Roku servers. If you choose to remove cookies or reject cookies, this could affect certain features or services of Roku Sites. To learn about opting-out of certain third party analytics tracking on the Roku Sites, see, for example:  [Google](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout), [Optimizely](https://www.optimizely.com/opt_out), [Bazaarvoice](http://www.bazaarvoice.com/privacy-policy/#whatarecookies), and [Crazy Egg](https://www.crazyegg.com/opt-out) opt-out pages.  You can also choose to opt-out of use of cookies by many of Roku’s third party advertising partners to deliver ads tailored to your profile and preferences by visiting the [Digital Advertising Alliance in the USA](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/), [Digital Advertising Alliance in Canada](http://youradchoices.ca/) or the [Digital Advertising Alliance in Europe](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/). If you delete your cookies, use a different browser, or buy a new computer, you will need to renew your opt-out choices. If you do not want us to track emails we send you, some email services let you change your display to turn off HTML or disable download of images which should effectively disable our email tracking, or you may unsubscribe from our marketing emails as described in those emails. While we and others give you choices described in this Privacy Policy, there are many ways Web browser signals and other similar mechanisms can indicate your choice to disable tracking, and we may not be aware of or honor every mechanism.

### Roku Device and channel RIDA choices

If you check “Limit Ad Tracking” on your Roku Device, Roku will not serve personalized ads to you on that Roku Device based on information tied to that device’s RIDA. You will, however, still see ads on your Roku Device, but these ads will be less relevant as they will not be customized based on the RIDA for your Roku Device. Your selection will affect only the ads on your Roku Device. In addition, Roku will make available to channel providers your preference that they not use your RIDA to display personalized ads on your Roku Device. Roku, however, cannot guarantee that such channel providers will honor your preference. For information on a specific channel provider’s advertising and privacy practices, you should consult that channel’s privacy policy. 

You can also reset the RIDA on your Roku Device. When you reset the RIDA for your Roku Device, the original identifier will no longer be used to display personalized ads on that Roku Device. A new identifier will be assigned for that purpose.

## Part V.  Data Storage, Transfer and Security

Roku uses industry-standard methods of securing its electronic databases of personal information. However, you should know that no company, including Roku, can fully eliminate security risks associated with personal information. To help protect yourself, please use a strong password, do not use the same passwords to access your Roku accounts that you use with other accounts or services, and protect your user names and passwords to help prevent others from accessing your accounts and services.

Information collected by Roku or on our behalf may be stored on your Roku Devices, on your mobile device if you use the Roku Mobile App, or on our servers, and may be transferred to, accessed from, or stored and processed in, the United States, EU member state countries, India, the Philippines and Costa Rica, and any other country where Roku or its service providers maintain facilities or call centers, including jurisdictions that may not have data privacy laws that provide protections equivalent to those provided in your home country. However, we will protect all personal information we obtain in accordance with this Policy. By using any Roku Device, Roku Site, Roku Mobile App, creating a Roku account, or connecting with Roku’s social networking accounts, you consent to our transfer of your personal information in accordance with this Policy. Personal information we collect may be retained for as long as needed to fulfill legitimate business purposes, including the purposes outlined in the “Information Usage” section above, or for a period of time specifically required or allowed by applicable regulations or laws.

## Part VI.  Your California Privacy Rights

A California resident who has provided personal information to a business with whom such resident has established a business relationship for personal, family, or household purposes (a “California Customer”) may request information about whether the business has disclosed personal information to any third parties for the third parties’ direct marketing purposes.  In general, if the business has made such a disclosure of personal information, upon receipt of a request by a California Customer, the business is required to provide a list of all third parties to whom personal information was disclosed in the preceding calendar year, as well as a list of the categories of personal information that were disclosed.  California Customers may request information about our compliance with this law by e-mailing [customer.advocate@roku.com](mailto:customer.advocate@roku.com).  Please note that we are required to respond to one request per California Customer each year, and we are not required to respond to requests made by means other than through this e-mail address.

## Part VII.  Modifications

We may amend this Privacy Policy at any time by posting the amended version on the applicable Roku Site.

## Part VIII.  Contact Information

If you have any questions regarding this Privacy Policy, please contact us at [customer.advocate@roku.com](mailto:customer.advocate@roku.com).

 _Roku is located at 12980 Saratoga Avenue, Suite D, Saratoga, CA 95070_

Copyright © 2008-2015 Roku, Inc. All rights reserved. Roku and the Roku logo are trademarks or registered trademarks of Roku, Inc.
